SHAHBAZ HAIDER

Front-End Developer

Phone no: 9031153945 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/shahbazhaider2552/

Email: mshaider2111@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://shahbaz-haider21.github.io/portfolio/

Address: Bengaluru, Karnataka, India, 560076 GitHub: https://github.com/shahbaz-haider21

Knowledgeable front-end developer working as a freelancer for 1 year, and now aiming to resume a rewarding career in software engineering. I have pursued certification through remote learning in Web development. My keen interest in programming and developing visually appealing websites.

Skills:

- Expert in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Knowledge of CSS preprocessors like Sass or Less.
- Experience working with APIs and integrating frontend with backend services.
- Familiarity with design tools like **Figma**, and **Adobe XD**.
- Proficient in using Git for version control.
- Understanding of techniques for improving web page performance and loading times.
- Expertise in building responsive and mobile-friendly websites.
- Knowledge of media queries and responsive design principles.

Work Experience:

Freelance Frontend developer

2023 - Present

- Developed responsive multi-browser compatible websites using modern web technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Revamped website using responsive web design techniques, resulting in a 40% increase in mobile conversions and a 25% boost in overall user engagement and satisfaction.
- Optimized website performance by implementing techniques like image compression, and minification of CSS and JavaScript files.
- Created Navigation bar, Dropdown menu, Image Carousel, Button, Modal, Form, Table, Tabs, Pagination using Bootstrap.
- Used Ajax in JSON/ jQuery format for asynchronous request handling and partial refreshing by the user.
- Performed bug fixes and code review.
- Used GIT as version control system.

Planned Career Break 2017 – 2022

- Took intentional pause to pursue Civil-services exam preparation, now aiming to resume a rewarding career in software engineering.
- During this time, actively pursued certification through remote learning in UI development, succeeding through outstanding self-management skills and strong ability to focus.

Certification:

JavaScript Certification

Skills Covered: JavaScript fundamentals, DOM manipulation, AJAX, Regex

Education:

Bachelor of Engineering
 Civil Engineering, Kurukshetra University, India

2012 - 2016